If yet your blood does not rage, then it is waterthat flows in your veins.
如果血液不沸騰, 血管裏流的就是水
For what is the flush of youth, if it is not of service to the motherland.
青春美好有何用, 如果不奉獻給祖國
British Indian, early twentieth century
[英屬印度, 二十世紀初]
Just a minute Mr. McKinley, one revolutionary is meeting another.
稍等McKinley先生, 一個革命者遇見了另一個革命者
Thank you. Shall we go?
謝謝. 走吧?
I'm sorry it had to end this way.
抱歉必須這樣結束
This isn't the end Mr. McKinley. This is just the beginning.
這不是結束McKinley先生, 而是開始
There will be others after we have gone. Many others.
我們死後還會有更多, 更多
I always believe there are 2 kinds of people in this world
我一直認為世界上有兩種人
Men that go to death screaming
面對死亡哭喊的人
Men who go to that death in silence
面對死亡安靜的人
Then I met a third kind
然後我遇到了第三種
Sometimes in my dreams I can still see them making that long last walk
有時在夢裏, 我仍見到他們最後一次走過
They never folded
他們沒有畏縮
they never
沒有嘗試掙扎
but above all of else
尤其記得的
I remember his eyes
是他們的眼睛
How they looked at me
看著我的神情
clear, defined, never wavering
清澈, 堅定, 毫不退縮
It's time
時間到
Rang De Basanti
片名: 芭薩堤的顏色 /Basanti: 春季, 又意金黃, 印度的愛國色彩/
So Sonia, my contact in delhi she's found some..
我在德裏的聯繫人Sonia正在尋找演員
We are gonna have to worry with some money to securite it
但是目前擔心的是經費
Everything's cash out there
那邊什麼都是現金
Have I come to the wrong meeting?
我走錯房間了嗎?
We've had a directive from above- budget cot
我們收到上面的指示: 縮減經費
So we've had to take some very tough decisions
所以我們必須做出艱難的決定
sorry, Sue
抱歉, Sue
really sorry
真的很抱歉
If you do the episode, then Ghadi, that'll work for us - Ghandi sells
如果要做, 甘地是沒問題 - 甘地有賣頭
I suggest.., even Robin Hood, but..
可以是.. 甚至羅賓漢, 可..
This revolution, is this, Bhagat Singh
這個革命, Bhagat Singh
Chandrashekhar Ali..
Chandrashekhar Ali?
Azad, OK?
Chandrashekhar Azad azad, OK?
and azad means freedom
而且Azad意思是自由
azad sorry, I know what it means, Sue
Azad, 對不起. 我知道它的意思, Sue
I don't belive this
我不相信
You know everything is set up, I've been working on this for 2 years. I've been going to bloody indian night classes
什麼都準備好了, 這個花了兩年 我甚至還去上了夜校印度課程
look, please
瞧, 拜託..
this story deserves to be told
這個故事值得講述
This is my grandfather's diary, he was an eye witness
這是我爺爺的日記, 他親眼見證
it's filled with real conversations, they have very words
寫滿了真實的對話, 每個字都有
boys, no older than 23 fighting the empire
勇士們, 23歲正好抗擊帝國
that's an important story, a bloody important..
這是個重要的故事, 非常重要的..
This is not the end, Mr. McKinley,
這不是結束McKinley先生
Can I talk to you?
能和你談談嗎?
Where are you going?
你要去哪?
To India, to shoot a documentary
去印度, 去拍紀錄片
I'll send you a postcard
我會給你寄明信片
How? with what?
怎麼寄? 用什麼寄?
Shove it.
操你
Get out of the way! Scoot!
讓開!
You come India first time madam? Yes!
夫人別緊張, 第一次來印度?
Are you married? Even me and my wife get married
結婚了嗎? 我和我的妻子也結婚了
Excuse me, she's with me
不好意思, 是我來接她的
Good to see you - I can't believe you are here. It's happening at last
見到你真好 - 不敢相信你來了, 終於見到你了
Sorry about the short notice.
對不起沒有早點通知你
Gosh! Your Hindi has really improved.
天! 你的印地語說得真好
Hey Sue, no need to worry...
沒有什麼可擔心的
...everything has been taken care of posters have been put up everywhere.
什麼都齊了, 到處都做了宣傳
It's also been announced on radio.
還在廣播裏說了
...just see, they'll be lining up forthe auditions.
看吧, 人會排著對來試鏡的
What's wrong?
怎麼了?
I didn't tell you. The truth is that I've come alone.
我沒跟你說, 其實我是一個人來的
...no money, no producer is going to arrive.
沒有錢, 也沒有製片人來
I know
我知道
You knew it!
你知道?
After Alice, there was a call from a certain Beth Williams...
有個叫Beth Williams的, 來了電話..
...she informed me of the cancellation of the show and also my services.
她通知我計劃取消, 你也辭職了
...did you abuse her in Hindi?
順便問下, 你是不是用印地語罵她了?
She wanted to know what it meant. I explained to her in graphic detail.
她想知道什麼意思, 我跟她說了, 仔細地解釋了一遍
You are amazing... Sonia.
你真是不可思議, Sonia
This is Delhi University
這是德裏大學
Let me help you with your luggage.
我來幫你拿行李
How much? - Ma'am I've already told you.
多少錢?                          夫人已經說了
Ravi, please get all the luggage to our room.
Ravi, 請把行李搬到我的房間
Which country, madam?
哪個國家, 女士?
India, I hope
印度, 我希望
Get some rest now. I'll see you tomorrow...
休息一下, 我明天再來
...lf you need anything you have my number.
要有什麼需要, 打我的電話
Let's go Ravi.
我們走吧, Ravi
My grandfarther is right
我爺爺說得沒錯
He said when you come to India, it's love of a first sight
他說你要是來印度, 會一見鍾情
Hi, it's double speaking
我是Dabul
My hobbies are, bikes, babes, and body building
我的愛好是摩托, 美人, 和健美
I can't do this.
我不行
Just try once
試一下
I can't do this.
我不行
I deserve a role because I have dimples just like Priety Zinta.
我應該出演, 因為我跟Priety Zinta一樣有酒窩
- Vande Matram? Don't sing. Just recite "Vande Matram". - Vande Matram?
不要唱, 就複述"Vande Matram"
Raise your hand and say VANDE MATRAM! VANDE Matram!
舉起手來說: Vande Matram
Speak loudly, VANDE MATRAM! Vande MATRAM.
說大聲點, Vande Matram!
Loudly and proudly, VANDE MATRAM! Vande MATRAM
響亮地說: Vande Matram
I have dedicated my life to the freedom of this nation.
我把生命獻給了祖國的自由
I know you want me to get married.
我知道你希望我結婚
...but FREEDOM is my bride.
但自由就是我的新娘
I know... I know... that...
我知道.. 我知道.. 嗯..
I know... that you want me to get married...
我知道.. 你希望我結婚
...but my bride is FREEDOM
但自由就是我的新娘
Your obedient son, BHAGAT SINGH.
你順從的兒子, Bhagat Singh
BHAGAT SINGH.
Bhagat Singh
Bhagat Singh.
My name is Bhagat Singh.
我的名字叫Bhagat Singh
Tea!
茶?
Thanks.
謝謝
Depressed huh?
有些失望, 對嗎?
One or two of them can be used for minor roles...
有一兩個還是可以出演
...but no one's even close for Azad or Bhagat Singh.
但Azad, Bhagat Singh, 沒有接近的
I guess it's all my fault.
我想, 這都怪我
No Sonia. You're my rock.
不Sonia, 你是我的堅強後盾
It's my fault
是我的錯
I should never have come
我不該來
Sue, don't get so dejected.
瞧Sue, 不要這麼灰心
I think we need a break
我看我們得放鬆下
Let's go and have some fun. I'm in no mood Sonia.
走, 我們去玩下.                    我沒有心情
Come on, we are going to the classroom
來吧, 我們去教室
Come on
來啊
Aslam... Sue McKinley.
Aslam... Sue McKinley
You too study at the University?
你也在大學裏學習嗎?
Wow! Her Hindi is great.
哇, 她的印地語真好
We live there, eat there but no one has ever accused us of studying there.
我們在那住, 在那吃 可還沒人咒過我們在那學習
What are those maniacs upto?
那些瘋子幹嗎?
That's DJ...
那是DJ
DJ I love you!!!
DJ我愛你!
That's Sukhi.
還有Sukhi
DJ I love you!!!
DJ我愛你!
I love you too baby!
我也愛你寶貝!
Damn exhibitionists.
他媽的表現狂
The idiots will never change.
那白癡就是改不了
Come on dude, let's rock it!
來吧夥計, 我們喝翻天!
Sukhi I love you!
加油, Sukhi, 我愛你!
Is he OK?
他沒事嗎?
That's his natural state.
Sukhi就喜歡這樣
Sukhi, all parts working?
怎麼樣Sukhi, 身子還好使吧?
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
我的媽! Sonia旁邊的是誰?
Sue this is DJ. DJ this is Sue.
Sue, 這是DJ. DJ這是Sue
Sue? She's so pink her name should be Gulabo (Rose).
Sue? 她這麼紅潤該叫Gulabo(玫瑰)才對
She's quite hot...
真是個"辣妹"
Perfect for this cold.
我是說, 真冷啊.. (用英語說, 以為Sue不懂印地語)
Karan you saved my life. I love you!
Karan, 你救了我的命, I love you
Aslam...
Aslam..
...you too saved my life,
你也救了我
I love you too!
I love you too
It's ok.
好吧..
She must have saved my life too...
她肯定也救了我的命..
No! Sukhi! She didn't save your life.
不, Sukhi! 她沒救你的命
No problem. One day she'll save my life.
沒關係, 有一天她會救我的
Relax Dude! She is your sister-in-law.
放鬆點夥計, 是你嫂子呢
LOOSE CONTROL
失去控制
I'm a REBEL.
我是叛逆
There's aren't any students here, no teachers to suffer.
這裏沒有學生, 沒有老師管教
It's a school without rules out here Hey Genius, go figure.
這是沒有教條的學校 聰明的傢伙, 好好去想吧
Sukhi you just sit and watch like a dumb-ass...
你就這樣傻坐著?
DJ doesn't waste a second.
DJ可一秒也不放過
He's a stud.
他是個人物
Hi! How's everybody? Hi Rahul! What's up?
大家怎麼樣?             嗨Rahul, 還好吧
Got a few gigs lined up.
一大堆工作
How's your radio thing going?
廣播電台搞得怎樣了?
Did anything work out?
順利麼?
All India Radio has given me a night slot.
"全印"電台給了我晚間檔
Cool...
不錯啊
Not really. When the whole world's sleeping I'm on air.
不完全是. 人們都睡覺了, 我就在播音
But people stay up late...
有人也經常熬夜
Criminals, insomniacs, watchmen and idiots!
罪犯, 失眠患者, 保安, 還有白癡!
Have your fun at my expense.
你們就拿我的損失開玩笑吧
Speaking of expenses... Can I...
說到損失, 我能不能..
Thanks, Man
謝謝夥計
See you guys. Got a cigarette?
先走了. 有湮沒?
Fabulous!
難以置信
It's my Dad's money. He's got lots of it...
是我爸的錢, 他有的是錢
Stop this Western music, this obscenity!
不許放污穢的西方音樂
How many times do I have to make you understand this!
還要說多少遍?
Polluting the culture of this country...
把國家的文化都污染了
Leave this place right now. LEAVE!
現在馬上走人, 滾!
Can't you understand, idiot!
你怎麼就不明白, 笨蛋!
This is your last warning...
這是最後一次警告!
...from now on, nobody plays any Western music out here.
從現在起, 這裏再沒有西方音樂
No lewd dancing!
沒有下流舞蹈
Or I'll break your legs.
不然就打斷你們的腿!
Who are you to warn us? If you don't like it, don't come here.
憑什麼來警告我們? 你不喜歡就別來
You bloody Pakistani!
你他媽的巴基斯坦人
Let's finish it.
我們來做個了斷
Last warning! Got it?
最後的警告, 聽明白了?
Long live India!
印度萬歲!
You touch Aslam and see what I do to you...
你們敢動Aslam, 讓你們好看..
...even your mother won't recognize you.
讓你媽都認不出來你
Ever seen a baboons arse? Yours will be as red after I've finished with you.
見過猴子屁股沒? 收拾完你讓你一樣紅
Sir, I'm sure we can work it out.
長官, 我們會解決的
Keep this...
拿著..
Is that a bribe?
那是賄賂嗎?
Welcome to India, Sue
歡迎來印度, Sue
Anyone hungry? I'm famished.
有人餓了沒? 我都飢腸轆轆了
Hey Sue, Want a ride?
Sue, 想坐車嗎?
You got a insurance, no?
你有保險沒?
How're you?
怎麼樣?
Hey honey! Come here you...
寶貝! 快過來..
If something happened to you, I'd have killed you.
你要出了什麼事, 我饒不了你
Is this any way to greet your boyfriend?
你就這樣迎接你男朋友?
How're you?
還好嗎?
Fligh Lt. Ajay Rathore
空軍上校Ajay Rathore
Don't miss that
就是我
Hurry guys, I'm famished.
快點, 我都要餓死了
You won't get any food here.
這沒有你們吃的
Dear Ma, I'm hungry - You do not get anything
親愛的老媽, 我餓了                    什麼"老媽"
Stay away!
走開, 這也沒你吃的
...I carried you in my stomach for nine months...
我在肚子裏懷了你九個月
...and washed your bum for years.
又給你換洗了幾年的尿布
Get lost!
滾開!
Does anyone bother to check if Mitro is alive or dead?
也沒人想著來問問Mitro是死是活?
What's up?
怎麼了?
You're drunk again.
你又喝醉!
No. No. No.
不不..
First give us food ma, and then yell at us all night.
媽先去拿點吃的, 整晚說我們都行
None of you have eaten?
你們都沒吃飯嗎?
Sonia you've lost even more weight.
Sonia你變得更瘦了
Really... Mitro
真的? Mitro
The girls of today have more bones and less flesh...
現在的女孩子都是骨頭, 肉倒少了
How will you bear children?
還怎麼生孩子啊?
Aslam, how are you my son?
Aslam, 你還好嗎孩子?
He is my true son who bothers to check on me.
他才是我真正的兒子, 問問我情況
And you...
而你這小子..
don't give a care
走了這麼久也沒消息                    哪有啊
Look ma, what I brought for you.
看啊媽, 我給你帶誰來了
Your daughter-in-law. Her name is Sue.
你的媳婦, 她的名字叫Sue
What? Aforeigner?
一個外國人?
Brought her especially from London. That's why I was away for so long.
專程把她從倫敦帶過來, 所以離開了這麼久
I am telling her London first of yours
我告訴她你從倫敦來
Give me your blessings Ma.
請祝福我, 媽
Your son's such a brat.
您兒子真調皮
God!
我的老天!
She understands Hindi!
她懂印地語?
You really understand everything? Yes.
你真的都聽得懂?
I'm going off to sleep. Your beds are all ready. No need to drive so late at night.
我要去睡覺了, 你們的床鋪都準備好了 不要熬到太晚
I saw the man, like they leaped out of grandpa's story
我看到了那些人, 彷彿從爺爺的故事中跳了出來
Bhagat Singh, Chandrashekhar Azad, Ashfaqulla Khan, Rajguru and Durga Bhabhi
Bhagat Singh, Chandrashekhar Azad,  Ashfaqulla Khan, Rajguru 還有Durga Bhabhi
They were sitting right there in front of me
他們就坐在我前面
Sue, where are you?
在想什麼呢?
Will you guys act in my film?
你們能在我電影裏演出嗎?
What?
什麼?
You guys acting in my film, you guys are perfect
在我的電影裏演出, 你們再合適不過
Hey, why are you guys laughing? I'm the hero of her film.
你們笑什麼? 我是她電影裏的男主角
Yeah we guys are champions when it comes to acting...
演戲我們是好手
...clowning around is all they do.
整天他們就會搞怪
I'm serious, OK?
我是認真的
The four of you will be perfect for the roles...
你們演Bhagat Singh, Chandrashekhar Azad, Ashfaqulla Khan, Rajguru非常合適
And Sonia will be my Durga Bhabhi.
而Sonia就做我的Durga Bhabhi
She really knows Hindi!
她真的懂印地語
All this talk of patriotism is boring.
說這些愛國主義很無聊
Boring? These guys gave their lives for the freedom of your country.
無聊? 他們為了你們國家的自由獻出了生命
What freedom? Have you seen the state of this country?
什麼自由? 你見過這國家的狀況嗎?
Excuse me! I believe in this country, Karan.
等下, Karan. 我國家有信心
Otherwise, why would I be fighting for it?
要不然, 我努力都是為了什麼?
Maybe because it's cool! Being a pilot... flying an expensive plane.
也許是因為很酷.. 開著昂貴的飛機
You get to wear sexy jackets...
穿著帥氣夾克
And the women... women love men in uniforms.
還有女孩子.. 女孩子喜歡制服男人
Sure I love being a pilot. Sure it's cool.
當然我喜歡做飛機員, 很酷
But I also feel proud of my country, and I can give my life for it.
但我也為祖國自豪, 能為她獻出生命
Proud of what?
有什麼自豪?
...this country's exploding population?
人口激增?
...or unemployment... or corruption?
或高失業率?                          還是腐敗?
Which of these are you really proud of?
哪一樣讓你感到自豪?
No country's perfect Karan. We've got to make it better.
得了夥計, 沒有完美, 只有讓它變得更好
Right.
對
Ok, Ajay you make this country perfect.
好, Ajay, 你讓國家變得更好
The minute I get my degree I'm out of this dump...
我一拿到學位就去美國, 離開這個垃圾場
You won't be able to leave us and go.
你沒這個能耐
Wait and see
等著瞧
She speaks Hindi so well!
她印地語真的不錯!
Why didn't you tell me you idiot. I was making a fool of myself.
你們怎麼不早說, 害我出醜
At least ask them once.
起碼跟他們說說, 求你
So you won't give up.
看來你是不放棄
Ok. But nobody will turn up.
OK, 不過他們不會去的
I'll get them. That's a promise.
我會, 我跟他們說, DJ答應你
Karan put your cigarette out.
Karan, 把煙熄掉
Grandpa!
爺爺
God bless you. When did you come?
老天保佑, 什麼時候來的?
Just last night.
昨晚上
Who?
是誰?
DJ's grandpa
DJ的爺爺
Good morning Karan.
早啊Karan
Back so early?
這麼早就回來了?
I didn't know you were in town.
我不知道你在家
Just arrived an hour ago.
一小時前剛到
It was a long flight...
飛了很久
Everything Ok at college?
大學裏還好吧?
Everything's fine Dad.
都好, 爸
Have you decided which American university you want to go to next year?
等下, 想好明年去哪所美國大學沒?
Michigan, Carnegie, Mellon, Wharton...
密歇根, 卡內基, 梅隆, 沃頓..
I know the list.
我知道有哪些
Karan wait!
等等
I can't hear you clearly call me later.
我聽不清楚, 等下打過來
I know that you know about the lists.
我知道你也清楚有哪些大學
But life doesn't just happen to you.
但生活不會自己創造
You've got to plan it...
需要你來規劃
Every second someone is born in this country.
這個國家每秒都有人出生
Nobody cares about them. Neitherthe government nor God.
沒人關心他們, 政府沒有老天也沒有
No
不用
Do something. Or else you will be one of them.
做點什麼, 不然會成為他們一員
Please, don't start with your lectures.
拜託不要跟我說教了
SMS generation
簡化主義
Any conversation that goes beyond four lines becomes a lecture.
超過四句話都成了"說教"
Signal's weak here. Give me a second. Excuse me Karan.
這信號不好. 稍等, 走開下Karan
Now shoot
好了說吧
The deal is off then
那就把交易取消
we are not interested...
我們不感興趣..
You know Russian quality is doubtful, they can't afford to be arrogant.
俄國貨本來質量就難說, 憑什麼自大?
Anyway in the open market they'd not get anything close to the price we're offering.
反正我們的出價, 比市場上高很多
And you know how many fathers there are to every deal in India. Nothing.
你也知道在印度, 每次交易都沒人負責
Tell them we won't bargain, they should wire the money to us.
跟他們說我們不談價, 他們該把錢匯給我們
I did try to warn you... they won't turn up.
我就說的, 他們不會來的
DJ promised me.
不, DJ答應過我
Oh! DJ promised you!
哦! DJ答應過你
So you really are a filmmaker?
你們真的是拍電影的
Karan... Why are you so late?
Karan.. 怎麼這麼晚?
And where are the others?
其他人呢?
The Young Guns Of India
印度年輕槍手
Very dramatic.
令人印象深刻
Where are you going?
你要去哪?
Well that's one part cast.
走, 這也是選角的一部分
I am sure Karan can tell us where his friends are.
我肯定Karan會告訴我們他的朋友們在哪
She's an eight. Yeah!
八分
Wow! Nine.
哇, 九分
What a girl! Oye Chotu...
多好的女孩! Oye Chotu...
...get me a cup of tea...
給我杯茶
Two, looks like she's got the flu...
二分, 讓她走人
Six...
六..
Ten! What?
十!                             什麼?
Dude... Iooks at those legs!
夥計.. 看那雙腿!
Shake it baby, shake it...
擺起來寶貝, 左右..
Oh shit!
哦糟糕!
Don't be silly, that's at least an eight.
別傻了, 起碼也有八分
Thought I'd find you stuffing your faces.
就知道你們在這貪吃
You lazy good-for-nothings.
這幫懶鬼, 幹不出什麼好事
We were about to come... but...
我們正想去的..
...we are waiting for Karan actually.
其實是在等Karan
Oh! So you were waiting for Karan. Yeah!
是嗎? Karan?
Karan was there on time.
Karan準時去了
We are waiting for him here and he was waiting for us there.
我們在這等, 他卻在那等
What confusion...
把我們搞得暈頭轉向
You're Ashfaqulla Khan.
你是Ashfaqulla Khan
You're Rajguru. The hero right!
你是Rajguru                              主角對嗎?
And you know who you are?
你, 知道是誰嗎?
The Master of Disguise and Deception.
偽裝騙術大師
Chandrashekhar Azad.
Chandrashekhar Azad
What lips...
嘴唇真性感..
Learn the lines properly, we meet tomorrow.
好好看台詞, 我們明天見
8 a.m. Sharp!
八點準時排演!
Nine
九..
Sharp at eight.
八點整!                        哦八點
We've already wasted a day...
我們已經浪費一天了
Aslam, your sister-in-law looks even better when she's angry.
Aslam, 你嫂子生氣時更好看了
What are you doing Laxman?
在幹什麼呢, Laxman?
Party High Command is really happy with your work.
黨高層對你的工作很滿意
These demonstrations that you have started against Western culture...
你牴觸西方文化做的努力
...they've helped us overshadow other parties.
令其它黨派相形見絀
This is for you. And this is for your boys.
這是給你和你的朋友的
It's not necessary, Mishraji.
沒有必要, Mishraji
I'm not doing this for money.
我是為了黨不是為了錢
I really believe in the principles of my party.
我真的相信我黨的理念
That's fine Laxman...
很好Laxman..
...but every movement needs fuel... Keep it.
但每次行動也需要燃油.. 拿著
March the 14th
3月14日
We started the rehearsals
我們開始了排演
To say I was nervous would be an understatement
說我是緊張遠遠不夠
There is nothing you can do to break me.
沒有什麼能把我打倒
"Because I have made pain my friend."
因為疼痛是我的朋友
"...As I hold Death's fingers."
因為我緊握死亡的手指
DJ idiot, don't spoil my concentration.
DJ傻瓜, 不要影響我集中注意力
Please guy, be serious
大家認真點
Look, Death's finger.
看啊, 死亡的手指..
"I've committed my life to the freedom of this country.
我已把自己獻給了國家的自由
...I know you want me to get married, but I have made freedom my bride..."
我知道你希望我成家, 但自由就是我的新娘
"Your obedient son, Bhagat Singh."
你順從的兒子, Bhagat Singh
Who talks like this for God's sake?
誰會這麼說? 你順從的兒子
My bride is freedom...
自由是我新娘, 他有什麼問題?
I think it's a good line for Sukhi...
我看這句台詞對Sukhi挺合適
Since no girl is ever going to marry him...
反正也沒有女孩子會嫁給他
Let freedom be his bride.
就讓自由作他的新娘吧
Laugh bastards, laugh.
笑吧混蛋, 笑吧
This is the sari round of the Miss Freedom contest.
看啊, 是"自由小姐"競選穿的紗麗
Just thought it would help me get into the character.
這樣能讓我感受角色
Look guys this isn't going to work.
這樣是不行的
You have to work hard to bring out the characters.
你們要認真地感受角色
Unless you emote from within...
只有用心表演..
...you won't understand these characters.
你們才會理解這些角色
Try... it will come from within you.
試一下.. 會從你們內心流露出來
See, he's got a hold of his character already.
他已經抓住他的角色了
You understood the character pretty fast.
你理解人物挺快的
Would you stop it?
不要胡鬧了
Just shut up and get out
住口一邊去
See! Now you look like a revolutionary!
看哪! 你看起來也完全是個革命者
Whatever you say Gulabo, you need me to create the mood.
Gulabo不管怎麼說, 你還需要我來創造情緒
DJ watch it.
DJ你看看
Now she's upset!
現在她沮喪了
Those are the words of a 23 year old.
Bhagat Singh才23歲, 這是他說的話
That's how old Bhagat Singh was when he died: 23.
這也是他犧牲的年齡
Those were different times Sue.
那個時代不同
Today, if you tell people that you want to give your life for your country...
現在, 你要是跟人說, 把生命獻給祖國
...they'll call you nuts.
他們會說你傻
Exactly.
正是
I don't think I can relate to this...
我覺得和我沒什麼共同點
That's it. Don't think.
行了, 不要想了
Feel. Just read the words, Feel them.
去感覺, 讀這些文字, 去感覺
Why don't we try again?
何不再來一次?
Let's try again...
再試一次
I've committed my life to the freedom of this country.
我已把自己獻給了國家的自由
...a job... a well settled life... these things don't matter anymore.
工作, 安定的生活, 都已經不再重要
...I know you want me to get married, but I have made freedom my bride...
我知道你希望我成家, 但是自由就是我的新娘
I swear on Mother India...
我, 印度母親的兒子, 在此莊嚴發誓..
This Aslam is a real stud...
Aslam是個人物..
Take a look at the packaging. Poetry, palmistry!
看看他的本事, 作詩, 相手..
DJ, I'm scared at times that I'll remain a bachelor all my life.
DJ, 我有時怕會單身一輩子
Trust me I won't let you die a bachelor.
相信我, 我不會讓你到死也是條單身漢
Promise?
保證?
It's DJ's promise.
這是DJ的保證
You'll be writing people's destinies...
你會書寫人們的命運..
Your love line is very strong...
你的愛情線很強
The man of your dreams will come along in a black T-shirt and say:
你命中的男人會穿著黑T恤到來, 並說:
Do I even have a love line?
我到底有沒有愛情線?
You must have washed it off in the loo.
你一定在廁所裏洗掉了
"Defence Minister Shastri has also been implicated in the MIG-21 kickbacks scandal,"
'國防部長Shastri也牽涉到MIG-21佣金醜聞'
This is really depressing.
真教人鬱悶
"This is a blatant lie. I am ordering an investigation."
'這是無恥的謊言, 我要求對此調查"
See you guys.
再見夥計
You're my buddy... I'll drop you home.
你是我夥計, 我送你回家
I don't need any help, it's just two lanes away.
我不需要幫助, 才兩條街
We aren't so drunk... that we've forgotten where you live.
我們沒醉到, 連你家都不記得在哪
Idiots!
一幫傻瓜
You're very lucky to have friends like them.
你有這樣的朋友很幸運
One day this will all end.
有一天都會結束的
We'll all go our separate ways.
我們會走上不同的路
But you can always keep in touch.
但是你們可以保持聯繫
Doesn't happen.
不會的
Life gets busy.
生活會變得繁忙
Too many problems. Getting a job, a house, money.
各種問題, 找工作, 房子, 賺錢
In college we are the masters of our destinies...
在學校我們是命運的主人
But after college we have to dance to fate's tune.
畢業後我們是命運的奴僕
You know Gulabo. I passed out 5 years ago...
知道嗎Gulabo, 我5年前就畢業了
...but I still hang around...
但我還在混..
I don't understand.
我不明白
...I don't ever want to leave college.
我一直不想離開學校
Why?
為什麼?
At least in the campus I'm someone... people know me.
起碼在學校人們認識我
DJ's somebody...
DJ是個人物..
People expect me to do something big in life.
人們對我抱有期望
But when I'm out on the streets...
但是等我出來了
I'll just be like the rest of the slobs in this country.
我不過就像國家的那些懶漢
Nameless. Faceless. Scared. Just walking the streets...
什麼也不是, 又怕
It's the beer... Everything came out.
喝了點酒, 把什麼都說了
You know what else I'm scared of?
你知道我還怕什麼?
Acting in your film.
在你的電影裏表演
Don't worry... you're in safe hands.
別擔心, 有可靠的人保護
Where have you been?
去哪了?
Hello Uncle... How are you?
你好大伯
We'll catch up tomorrow Aslam...
我們明天見Aslam
You've been drinking?
你喝酒了?
Dad, you know I don't drink.
爸, 你知道我不喝酒
Good-for-nothings... Whatever, they're my friends.
他們一無是處                     不管怎樣他們是我朋友
Friends! They feel no shame standing in front of...
什麼朋友! 他們不感到害臊..
...yourfather with alcohol on their breath.
滿口酒氣站在你爸面前
Why can't you get friends in your own community?
你怎麼不在我們的圈子裏找朋友?
Why do you make friends with people who corrupt you, disgrace your religion...
為什麼跟這些讓你敗壞, 污辱信仰的人?
This has nothing to do with religion, Father.
這跟信仰無關, 爸
Shut up!
閉嘴!
Don't raise your voice in the presence of yourfather.
跟你父親說話小心點
He's right.
他說得對
This country has never accepted Muslims and it never will...
這個國家從不接受穆斯林, 也絕不會
How can you be so passive!
你怎能這麼漠視?
Do you ever see me mixing with a Hindu?
你看見我跟印度教人混一起過嗎?
I'm not you and I don't want to be like you brother.
我不是你, 你也不像你一樣
I can't fill myself with so much hate...
我不能讓自己滿是仇恨
Coward that's what you are.
膽小鬼你這點是改不了的
Stop it!
不要說了
I feel suffocated in this house. It's the same old thing every single day...
我在這裏受夠了, 每天都是同樣的爭吵
Carnivals will be held on our graves every year,
我們的墓地每年都會有狂歡
That's all that will be left of us, when we die for our country.
我們為國家死後, 留下的就是這個
Well said Ashfaq Sahab...
說得好Ashfaq Sahab..
If the English could hear you they would leave this country in a moment.
英國人要是聽見, 馬上會離開
So what has been decided?
有什麼決定?
We'll steal the Empire's money from the train that passes Kakori.
有一輛火車經過Kakori, 我們在那偷帝國的錢
And with that money we will buy arms.
我們用那些錢來買武器
Bismil will explain everything.
Bismil會仔細解釋
Yes Bismil... Where is my Ram?
是Bismil.. 我的Ram在哪?
I just can't find my Ramprasad Bismil.
我還是找不到我的Ramprasad Bismil
Relax. We will find him.
放鬆, 會找到的
But where? How?
在哪? 怎麼找?
Very soon. Don't you wo...
很快, 你不是..
You won't get Ramprasad Bismil out here.
你們在這是不會找到Ramprasad Bismil的
You need a true Indian.
你們需要一個真正的印度人
How can you find Indian revolutionaries amongst...
你在一群想成為西方人的人裏..
...people who want to be Westerners?
怎麼找得到印度的革命家?
Ignore him. Let's go.
別聽他說, 我們走
Ramprasad Bismil wished to be reborn a hundred times...
Ramprasad Bismil希望重生100次..
...so that he could give his life for his country a hundred times over.
以此為他的祖國獻身100次
Let's go Sue.
我們走Sue
So where do you think I can find my Bismil?
那在哪才能找到我的Bismil?
I don't believe this.
真不敢相信
This day, we walk along with death, and laugh at its pale spectre.
這一天我們與死亡同行, 嘲笑它蒼白的臉龐
We will not fear those cruel swords, our courage is far sharper.
我們不懼怕殘忍尖刀, 我們的勇氣更為鋒利
Mistake not our silence for submission. For beneath lies lava, molten.
不要錯把沉默當成屈服, 後面是那滾滾熔岩
O Martyre, O men of valour. One day the enemy will sing your praises.
哦烈士, 哦英勇的人 有一天敵人也會讚頌你
We will show our mettle when the moment of truth arrives...
當真理來臨, 我們會顯示勇氣
...for courage lives in deeds, not boastful lies.
因為勇氣是行動, 而不是誇誇其談
We've gathered in the enemy's lair, my friend...
我們聚集在敵人的巢穴, 朋友們..
In the hope of dying for our motherland.
渴望為了祖國獻出生命
We will not fearthose cruel swords, our courage is far sharper.
我們不懼怕殘忍尖刀, 我們的勇氣更為鋒利
This day, we walk along with death, and laugh at its pale spectre.
這一天我們與死亡同行, 嘲笑它蒼白的臉龐
We will not fear those cruel swords, our courage is far sharper.
我們不懼怕殘忍尖刀, 我們的勇氣更為鋒利
Sue, this isn't London
Sue, 這裏不是倫敦
You don't know what kind of scum, men like Laxman Pandey are.
你不知道像Laxman Pandey這樣的人渣
Look Sue if he is a part of this, then I can't do the film.
瞧Sue, 他要是也參與進來, 那我不能來演
If you have any problems with me say it on my face.
你要是有問題, 當著我的面說
Don't stab me in the back like a coward.
不要像個懦夫在背後說壞話
Pandey leave! We don't want trouble...
Pandey你走開, 我們不想惹麻煩
Speak you coward. What were you saying?
說你呢懦夫, 你剛才說什麼?
Aslam, where are you going?
Aslam, 你去哪?
Coward, what were you saying?
懦夫你說什麼?
Hey you! How dare you hit Aslam?
嘿, 你竟敢打Aslam?
I'm sorry, I took you guys in my film.
對不起, 對不起我找了你們來拍電影
God knows what made me come here...
上帝知道是什麼讓我來這..
I was so stupid to pack my bag and come to the place where people are just looking for excuses to kill each other
我是那麼蠢, 收拾東西到這個 人人找借口自相殘殺的地方
Well at least now you all have one less excuse
至少現在你們又少一個借口了
Sue, we are sorry
Sue, 對不起
You know we've got a problem with Pandey. There's a lot of bad blood.
你知道我們跟Pandey有過節, 所以劍拔弩張
And if I stay, it's sure to happen again.
我要是留下來, 肯定還會出事的
No, Sue.
不不, 不會的
We've worked it out.
我們會處理好的
You won't have any problems.
不會給你惹麻煩的
Sue... we all know how much this film means to you.
Sue, 我們都知道這部電影對你多重要
We want to help you finish what you came here to do.
我們想幫你完成你來這的初衷
Everyone wants you to stay.
大家都想你留下
I want you to stay.
我想你留下
Say something...
說點什麼..
I'm scared
我害怕
Don't worry, you're in safe hands.
別擔心, 有可靠的人保護你
Come on... Get up... Come here.
來, 起來, 過來
She's not going anywhere.
她哪也不去了
Now just chill.
現在放鬆下
The next four weeks were the hardest in my entire life
接下來的四周是我一生最困難的
and the happiest
也是最快樂的
Take some soil of my land
"採取一些黃泥, 從這片土地"
the scent of this air...
"採取一些香氣, 從陣陣風裏"
Add the breath of my being, the throbbing of my heart...
"加上一些呼吸, 嗒個嗒個似鼓點"
And the zeal, that races through my blood...
"還有鮮紅血滴, 熱情蘊藏在這裏"
Take all these, and stir it. Then watch as it brings out the colour...
"把這些混在一起, 創造出新的顏色"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.
"並給我染上愛國的顏色, 朋友, 給我染上愛國的顏色"
Watch as it brings out the colour.
"給我染上愛國的顏色"
Bismil's sent a message...
Bismil傳出消息..
...that the Lucknow train...
勒克瑙的火車..
...carrying the Empire's money... will be looted by us in Kakori...
裝著帝國的錢財, 就在Kakori動手
...while eating Kakori kababs.
邊吃著Kakori的烤肉
And we will buy bombs with that money.
然後我們用錢買炸彈
Leave her alone... She will stop giving milk.
饒了它吧.. 要不然都不產奶了
Give colour to your dreams. And those of your people.
"染了我的夢想, 染了我的人民"
Give colour to your happiness. And your sadness too.
"染了我的歡樂, 染了我的悲傷"
Give colour to generations... Give colour to the field...
"染了許多世代, 染了這片土地"
Give colour to the beat of your heart. And that of your music.
"染了我的心跳和它的韻律"
Give colour to every cheek. Give colour to your eyes...
"染了鏡子裏我的倒影"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism my friend.
"朋友, 給我染上愛國的顏色"
Watch as it brings out the colour...
給我染上愛國的顏色
Take some soil of my land
"採取一些黃泥, 從這片土地"
the scent of this air...
"採取一些香氣, 從陣陣風裏"
Add the breath of my being, the throbbing of my heart.
"加上一些呼吸, 嗒個嗒個似鼓點"
And the zeal, that races through my blood.
"還有鮮紅血滴, 熱情蘊藏在這裏"
Take all these and stir it. Then watch as it brings out the colour.
"把這些混在一起, 創造出新的顏色"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend. Watch as it brings out the colour.
"再給我染上愛國的顏色, 朋友, 給我染上愛國的顏色"
Hey Short-stuff!
嘿小子
Did you get Bismil's message?
你收到Bismil的消息沒?
No. No! Then Listen...
沒有? 那聽著..
The train that's Kakori... will be looted in eight days.
八天後就動手搶Kakori的火車
It's loaded with the Empire's money.
它裝滿了帝國的錢
Will you loot it? No.
你會搶嗎?                           不會
We will be buying arms from it.
我們要用它來買武器
What will we buy? Arms...
買什麼?                           武器
Yes... Very Good... go now.
很好, 走吧
On a slow fire, won't you, put this passion to cook.
"用一點愛, 煽焙平穩的火焰"
Then as it simmers, add a babbling brook.
"讓它前行, 遇到了河流"
Add a river, and an ocean. Maybe a pot of water.
"並到了海洋, 再裝進水罐"
Then sprinkle a bit. Stir it all up.
"慢慢地撒, 輕輕地搖"
And watch as it brings out the colour.
"直到新的顏色誕生"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.
"給我染上愛國的顏色, 朋友, 給我染上愛國的顏色"
Bismil has sent a message...
Bismil傳出消息..
...the Lucknow train...
勒克瑙的火車
...which carries the Empire's money...
裝著帝國的錢財
...will be looted by us in seven days, in Kakori...
我們七天後在Kakori動手
And we will buy bombs with that money.
拿這些錢去買炸彈
Now paint the whole town with it. Paint your very being.
"塗了周圍村落, 塗了它的歡笑"
Paint your every vein with it. Paint it with a smile.
"高高興興地塗, 全心全意地塗"
Paint those childhood years, won't you. Paint the flush of youth.
"塗了那些童年, 塗了青春年華"
Don't hesitate, my friend.
"不要遲疑, 認真塗上色彩"
Paint your patriotism over everything.
"換上顏色, 塗上所有一切"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.
"給我染上愛國的顏色, 朋友, 給我染上愛國的顏色"
Take some soil of my land, the scent of this air.
"採取一些黃泥, 從這片土地"
Take some soil of my land
the scent of this air.
"採取一些香氣, 從陣陣風裏"
Add the breath of my being, the throbbing of my heart.
"加上一些呼吸, 嗒個嗒個似鼓點"
And the zeal, that races through my blood.
"還有鮮紅血滴, 熱情蘊藏在這裏"
Take all these and stir it. Then watch as it brings out the colour.
"把這些混在一起, 創造出新的顏色"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.
"給我染上愛國的顏色, 朋友, 給我染上愛國的顏色"
Watch as it brings out the colour.
"給我染上愛國的顏色"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.
""給我染上愛國的顏色.. 朋友"
The Kokori robbery of 1925
1925年的Kakori搶劫
That where it all started
都是從那時開始的
Nothing would ever be the same after that
從那以後一切都會改變
British Officers... around 20 to 25 of them.
英國官兵, 有20到25人
We have to call it off! We've nearly reached Kakori. Stop Ashfaq, quick.
計劃必須取消, Kakori就快到了, 快阻止Ashfaq
Ashfaq, stop!
Ashfaq, 停下
It's too late to back out now... Come on... Move!
現在退出太遲了
Get inside!
進去!
Keep the windows shut...
看好所有窗戶..
The keys!
鑰匙!
You won't get away with this.
你是逃不掉的
Give me the keys! - I don't have it.
給我鑰匙!                        我沒有鑰匙
Banwari get the sledge hammer.
Banwari, 準備錘子
I'll handle them. You go get the money...
我來對付他們, 你去拿錢
Kakori send shockwave to obvious establishment
Kakori事件引起了對這群人的注意
People have found new heroes
人們找到了新的英雄
But we had no one to blame but ourselves
而我們只能責怪自己
What we were hearing
我們聽到的
were the echoes of our own guns booming
是自己槍聲的迴響
I've committed my life to the freedom of this country.
我已把自己獻給了祖國的自由
Comfort, and other worldly desires do not attract me.
安逸, 其它世俗的追求打動不了我
I know you want me to get married and settle down...
我知道你希望我成家, 安定下來..
...like all parents do.
像天下父母一樣
But freedom is my bride.
但自由是我的新娘
I hope you'll forgive me. Your most obedient son, Bhagat.
請求你們原諒, 你們順從的兒子, Bhagat
Let's take a break.
我們休息一陣
Breakfast? No...
早餐? 不要..?
Put it there.
放在這
General Dyer? How can one even think of doing something like this?
Dyer將軍? 誰做得出這種事?
I can't believe that he actually killed more than 400 people at Jallianwala Baugh.
不敢相信他在Jallianwala Baugh殺害了400人
379... that was the official figure.
379, 這個是官方數字
Actually nearly 1000 people were butchered...
其實近1000人被殺害
Last year at the tomb of Peer Sai, I prayed for Daljeet's well being.
去年在Peer Sai陵, 我為Daljeet平安求的
Who's Daljeet?
誰是Daljeet?
We were the epitome of tolerance.
我們以前就是容忍的典型
Even an ant reacts. But we are conditioned to take everything lying down.
連螞蟻也會反抗. 可我們習慣對什麼都不反抗
Rubbish! It's today's generation which lacks the will to do anything
胡說! 是現今一代人缺乏行動的意願
Have you ever heard of Shaheed Uddham Singh?
Shaheed Uddham Singh聽過嗎?
He went all the way to London and killed that Dyer.
他一路跑去倫敦殺死了Dyer
...because he was also a part of the Jallianwala Baugh massacre.
因為他也經歷了Jallianwala Baugh大屠殺
Eat it Sonia. The butter will strengthen your bones.
吃吧Sonia, 黃油會讓你骨頭強硬
In Punjab every mother sends at least one son to the army.
在旁遮普每個母親至少要送一個兒子去軍隊
Why should we retreat? Sacrifice runs in our blood.
我們為什麼要退縮? 我們血液裏流淌著犧牲
Only idiots like DJ retreat.
只有像DJ這樣的笨蛋才退縮
Why does it always come back to me?
怎麼老是說回我?
Shut up and eat your paratha.
閉嘴吃你的煎餅
What is the most used word in this country? ADJUST!
這個國家用的最多的詞是什麼? "調整"
Six people sitting on a seat forfour... someone will squeeze in and say - 'Please adjust! '.
四個人的座位坐六個人.. 有人會擠進來說:請調整
Hey! Why are you adjusting?
你幹嗎要調整, 夥計?
Strange. Isn't it?
奇怪不是嗎?
We are being hunted like animals in our own country...
在自己的國家, 卻像動物似的被追捕
...Ashfaq you should cross the border and get to Afghanistan...
Ashfaq, 你應該逃到阿富汗去
...We have many Muslim friends there. You will be safe with them.
我們在那有很多穆斯林朋友, 你在那很安全
After all, you're one of their own.
何況, 你也是他們一員
One of their own? Hmm...
他們一員?
Why don't you think of me as one of your own?
你怎麼不把我當自己人?
Ashfaq... I never meant...
Ashfaq, 我不是這個..
I didn't mean to hurt you.
我沒想到會傷害你
This is your country as much as it is mine.
這是我的, 也是你的國家
You have a right to fight and die for it too...
你也有權利為她戰鬥和死亡
...Forgive me.
原諒我
Ram, let us not talk of dying...
Ram, 我們不要說死..
I pray, that we all live to see our grandchildren grow up in a free country.
我祈禱, 我們都能看到孫兒生活在印度自由的土地上
Ram run!
Ram, 跑!
Where are your other friends?
你的同夥在哪?
Where's Azad?
Azad在哪?
Azad was not a man to be found easily
Azad不是輕易能找得到的
A master of disguises
一個偽裝的高手
They appeared and vanished at will
他們來去自由
After months of frustration
幾個月的徒勞後
The breakthrough came for the British goverment
不列顛政府找到了突破點
Banwari, weakest revolutionary in captivity
Banwari, 囚禁下最弱的革命者
A man who had given us to whereabouts for Bismil and Ashfaqullah
給了我們Bismil和Ashfaqullah下落的人
agreed to be the bait to trap Azad
同意作餌引Azad上勾
We had found our Judas
我們找到了我們的猶大
Banwari!
Banwari
I loved those songs and dances
歌舞真讓人叫絕
Do they happen in your films? That's the reason we grow trees in this country...
你們電影裏有嗎? 這是我們種樹的原因..
to dance around them.
圍著它們跳舞
So where are we going?
我們去哪?
Special day, special place!
特別的一天, 特別的地點
Special DAY?
特別的一天?
It's amazing
讓人驚嘆
Ever since I was a kid I used to come here...
我還是小孩子的時候, 就經常來這
...to watch planes take off... and watch them till they don't disappear in the sky.
看飛機起飛, 直到消失在天際
What the hell are they doing?
他們是在幹嗎?
I don't believe them.
真是難以相信
Men!
男孩子!
Come on, face it, you'd love to do that really.
得了, 接受吧, 你也很想那麼做
What? Take my shirt off and howl at planes.
什麼? 脫掉衣服朝天空大叫?
I won't mind if you do.
你要是這樣我不介意
Dream on buddy...
你就做夢吧
Boys and girls and Sukhi...
男孩, 女孩, 還有女孩的跟屁蟲Sukhi..
Why me all the time?
怎麼老是我?
I want to make a special announcement...
我有一個特別的聲明
I was wondering if you'd like to spend the rest of your life with me...
我在想你願不願意跟我共度餘生
...that's in case you aren't doing anything important...
要是你沒什麼重要事情的話?
Will you please marry me?
你能嫁給我嗎?
Without saying a word, you steal my heart.
"不要言語, 帶我同行"
I'll find happiness by your side I can't stay apart
"哪有你的微笑, 就是我的終點"
My life tastes sweet now,
"這幸福, 終於領悟"
since you walked through that door.
"從此這生活, 變得甜如蜜"
When your arms wrap around me, I know I've found my shore.
"你懷抱的海岸, 我的船終停靠"
Without saying a word, you steal my heart.
"不要言語, 帶我同行"
Sweep through the streets of my mind like a gentle spring.
"入我心途, 好似那朦朧雨"
Walk through the corridors of my heart, fill the caravan of my dreams.
"夢想的旅行, 有了你的身影"
I sway to the song of your soul.
"你哼的曲調, 成了我的旋律"
Without saying a word, you steal my heart.
"不要言語, 帶我同行"
I'll find happiness by your side, I can't stay apart.
"哪有你的微笑, 就是我的終點"
The first thing that hit me about this man
這人第一次給我印象的
was his voice
是他的聲音
I knew then
然後我清楚
My job was not going to be easy
這不會是件輕鬆活
I'll come back later.
我過會再來
My prayers won't stop
我的祈禱不會停止
till my country gets its freedom.
直到我的祖國獲得自由
I don't think you can wait till then.
我看你不能等到那個時候
My name is James McKinley. I'm here to find out from you...
我名字是James McKinley, 我來這找出..
...where Azad and the other terrorists are hiding.
Azad和其它恐怖分子躲在哪裏
Not terrorists. Revolutionaries.
不是恐怖分子, 是革命者
Breaking a man
拷問一個人
Bit by bit
一點一點
They said it will get easy with time
他們說會隨時間而習慣
It never did
卻從來沒有
The torture went on for some time
酷刑持續了一段時間
But Bismil didn't break
Bismil沒有開口
Both men have pain their friend
兩個人都忍受痛苦
They didn't break
他們沒有招認
Instead
反而
They did something I've never seen any prisoner do before
他們做了我從沒見過別的囚犯做的事
On this day, we walk with death and laugh at its pale spectre.
這一天我們與死亡同行, 嘲笑它蒼白的臉龐
Death cannot take you Ashfaq, when you live in people's hearts and minds.
死亡不能壓垮你Ashfaq, 你活在人民的心中
I think it was the poetry, that held their soul together
我想是詩歌把他們連繫在一起
As the torture tore their body apart
當酷刑把他們的身體撕裂
The torture didn't work
酷刑沒有奏效
So we thought of other ways
於是我們想的別的辦法
This is the Holy Quran.
孩子, 這是聖可蘭經
Hindus like Bismil will create a country for themselves.
像Bismil這樣的印度教徒在創造他們自己的國家
What will a Muslim like you get out of it? They're just using you.
穆斯林沒好處而是被利用
He's not fighting for Hindu freedom, he's fighting for Hindustan's freedom.
他不是為印度教而戰, 是為印度自由而戰
But you won't be able to understand this.
但是, 你是不會明白的
You've been a slave so long you've begun to like it.
你做奴隸太久甚至都開始喜歡了
Tell us where Azad and the other terrorists are...
說出Azad和其它恐怖分子的藏身處
...You can still save yourself.
你們還能保住性命
19 December.
12月19號(全印非婆羅門結盟達成)
It's not yourfault...
這不是你的錯, McKinley先生
...you're only doing your duty.
你只是在履行職責
How can this be real?
這怎麼能真的發生?
Tell me
告訴我
告訴我!
How can this be the way of God
這怎麼會是神的道路?
Please look after the one, they'll arrive at your door
請照顧這些會到你門口的人
Oh my God
哦, 上帝
I'm utterly sorry I've vanity
非常抱歉我還有虛榮..
Hey guys, what's up?
夥計們, 怎麼樣?
Whats wrong? Did someone die?
有人死了嗎?
Sue... I haven't seen these guys so serious.
Sue, 我從沒見他們這麼嚴肅
What are you doing to my friends?
你對他們做了什麼?
It's not me... it's them. They've really begun to get into this.
沒什麼, 是他們.. 開始融入角色了
Hey Laxman, aren't you coming along?
Laxman, 不一起去嗎?
No. Some othertime.
不, 下次吧
Come on. It's my last night in town.
來吧, 是我在這的最後一晚了
I'm not really hungry.
不, 我很餓
Watch us eat then. Come on.
看我們吃, 走吧
Come on...
走吧..
To two lovebirds with the most insanely romantic engagement in the whole wide world...
為Sonia和Ajay, 敬兩人訂婚, 祝激情浪漫到永遠
I'm insane only about two things in my life.
我一生只為兩樣瘋狂
Sonia and flying.
一個是飛行, 一個是Sonia
You're lucky to feel so passionately about something.
你很幸福, 能對什麼充滿熱情
You have your poetry Aslam.
你有你的詩歌啊
Just like DJ has his singing.
就像DJ有他的歌唱
Everyone has passion for something inside them, they just have to find this 'thing'.
每人都有熱情, 只需找到是什麼
Just like our revolutionaries...
就像我們的革命者
...their passion for freedom was greater than their love for their own lives.
他們對自由的熱忱超過了自身
There's nothing in this world worth giving your life for. Nothing!
這世界沒什麼值得付出生命, 沒有
Correct
正確
Repeat.
重新來
Easy DJ...
悠著點, 喝很多了
Yes mama.
好, "媽媽"
There are things worth giving your life for Karan.
有值得付出生命的東西
Please.
說說看
Bhagat Singh, Azad, Bismil, Ashfaq.. Like what?
Look at Bhagat Singh and Azad and the rest of those guys.
They gave their lives for this country.
他們為了國家獻身
Look what happened. All for nothing.
結果呢? 白死了
It's a shit-hole today.
到現在也是個爛攤子, 又有誰在意?
I give a shit.
我在意
People like Ajay who fight for their country give a shit.
像Ajay這樣為國家奉獻的人在意
So that people like you can sleep peacefully.
所以你們才能睡得安穩
Sonia get real.
Sonia, 別感情用事, 現實點
Sonia's right.
Sonia說得對
Sue, it's all-fine for a foreigner like you to say all this...
Sue, 你是外國人說說還行
Out here we're fighting for basics.
可在這, 人民還在為生存根本奮鬥
...food, clothing and shelter.
食物, 衣服, 房屋
Out here you try to change things you'll get even more screwed.
在這你要想改變什麼, 只會變得更糟
Corruption is in our DNA.
腐敗簡直就刻在我們的基因裏
There is no future for this country.
這個國家沒有未來
She's talking about the past, you're thinking about the future...
她在講過去, 你卻想未來
One leg in the past and one leg in the future,
一隻腳在過去, 一隻腳在未來
that's why we're pissing on the present...
所以我們在現在"尿尿"
DJ, you just shut up
DJ, 你閉嘴!
For once in life get serious.
起碼認真一次
Karan, it's easy to sit on the outside and be a critic...
Karan, 置身事外評論很簡單..
...blaming others is even easier.
責怪他人更加簡單
Why don't you go out there and change things?
你們怎麼不出去改變這一切?
Take a stand.
勇敢站起來
Join politics, the police force, government and clean it up.
加入政界, 警局, 政府, 清理社會
But you won't! I'll tell you why...
可你們不會! 我告訴你們為什麼
Because that takes hard work
因為那要付出相當的努力
It's easier to crib.
抱怨要容易得多
Nothing's going to change.
什麼也不會變的
You can go to your grave trying... it won't make any difference.
你可以拚死嘗試, 但不會有什麼不同
Correct... the only difference will be how you go to your grave...
對.. 唯一的不同是怎麼死
DJ relax
DJ 悠著點
I'm not drunk. Am I drunk Sue?
我沒有醉, 我醉了嗎, Sue?
See, the director's word is final. Cut it!
看, 導演說了算. Cut
Where were we?
說到哪了?
The end up style
死法
On the way to our graves.
死後怎樣去墳場
We'll all be wrapped in white shrouds when we die.
我們死了都會包在裹屍布裏
Only Ajay will be wrapped in the national flag.
只有Ajay包在國旗裏
DJ stop it
DJ, 說夠了
Karan, you can say whateveryou want,
Karan, 隨你怎麼說
not even the street dogs will bark when we die.
我們死了連街上的狗都不會叫
But Ajay will get a 21 gun salute.
但Ajay會有21聲鳴槍致敬
Karan, this is for you.
Karan, 給你的
For me? Thanks dude.
給我的? 謝謝
The girls fall for him anyway...
反正女孩子不管怎樣都喜歡他
If anyone deserves the jacket, it's me.
夾克要給人的話, 也該給我
Wow! What a dutiful daughter-in-law.
哇! 大嬸, 多孝順的媳婦
Come on, touch your fiance's feet.
來吧, 摸未婚夫的腳
DJ's right. Touch my feet, madam.
DJ說得對, 來吧
See what women in this country have to put up with?
看到了, 我國的婦女要忍受多少規矩
I think DJ's right. You should respect your traditions.
我覺得DJ說得對, 你該遵守你的傳統
See, even Sue agrees...
看, 連Sue也同意..
...a woman's place is at her husband's feet.
一個女人的地位就是他丈夫的腳
These two can be such children.
這兩個真是孩子
They spend half their time fighting. The other half making up.
他們一半時間吵架, 一半時間和解
Sweetie-pie, can't you stay a while longer?
甜餅, 你就不能久待會?
No, I have to go...
不行, 我必須要走..
SWEETIE -PIE!
甜餅!
Shut up guys.
行了, 夥計們
Shut up yaar... Ma will hear everything.
閉嘴啊, 媽都聽到了
I know how Sonia must be feeling right now...
我知道Sue現在的感受
...my father was also in the army.
我父親以前也在軍隊
I used to think that way too...
我也曾經這樣想
...when Ajay's father and I first got married.
當時我跟Ajay他爸新婚
But then you realize something about being an Air-force pilot's wife.
然後想到做空軍飛行員的妻子
You realize that your husband has pledged his life forthe country.
想到丈夫已經把生命交給了國家
The least you can do for him, is control your emotions. Not be weak.
你能為他做的, 就是控制情緒不要脆弱
I'm so happy Ajay's chosen a girl like you...
我很高興, Ajay選了你這樣的好女孩
...now I can die in peace.
現在我可以安心死了
Don't talk nonsense Ma.
說什麼呢, 媽
You'll have many more years... ...and a dozen grandchildren too.
你還有很多時間, 跟很多孫子孫女呢
Grandchildren? First you've got to stay home long enough to make them, dude.
孫子孫女? 要有足夠時間來造人啊
The bugle sounds, the enemy wakes. The battle is upon us.
號角鳴響, 敵人出動, 戰鬥已來臨
And in our hearts, we feel the swell, of pride and steel and valour.
我們心裏, 自豪堅定, 和英勇在膨脹
For we will play the game of blood, if dark clouds shroud our land.
烏雲籠罩了大地, 我們誓死血戰
Because this day, we walk with death, and laugh at its pale spectre.
因為今日與死亡同行, 嘲笑它蒼白臉龐
We will not fear those cruel swords, our courage is far sharper.
我們不懼怕殘忍尖刀, 勇氣更為鋒利
We will not lower, in the face of threats, a head raised to its mother.
面對威脅絕不屈服, 仰頭向祖國母親
We will not fear those cruel swords, our courage is far sharper.
我們不懼怕殘忍尖刀, 勇氣更為鋒利
We will not lower, in the face of threats, a head raised to its mother.
面對威脅絕不屈服, 仰頭向祖國母親
For let them know, their cowardly deeds, just serve to stoke our fires.
讓他們知道怯懦行徑, 只會火上澆油
Because this day, we walk with death, and laugh at its pale spectre.
因為今日與死亡同行, 嘲笑它蒼白臉龐
We bade farewell, to this day, knowing it could be our last.
我們今天互相道別, 了知是自身的終結
We swore to play, with our lives, never waver in our task.
我們發誓獻出生命, 在戰鬥中絕不退縮
For we are but the last, few guests, served at fate's great banquet.
因在這命運的筵席, 我們是最後的賓客
We cannot quell, the raging storm, the spirit of revolution.
無法鎮壓狂怒的風暴, 是這革命的精神
For it now courses in our veins, like lava truly molten.
它流淌在我們的血液, 就像熔岩在滾動
We will teach them, the twin lessons, of fear and fortitude.
我們給他們兩個教訓, 便是恐懼和堅毅
Our goal cannot now hide for long, when courage is our beacon.
我們的目標埋藏不住, 勇敢是我們燈塔
Because this day, we walk with death, and laugh at its pale spectre.
因為今日與死亡同行, 嘲笑它蒼白臉龐
The entire country is in deep mourning of the Lalaji's death
整個國家都在悼念Lalaji的戰亡
Just before his death, Lalaji had said
就在Lalaji死前, 他說
Every blow ended me, is a nail in the coffin of British imperialism
每次抗擊都是英帝國主義棺材上的一顆釘
It was the calm before the storm
是暴風雨來臨前的寧靜
We have to take drastic measures.
我們必須採取嚴厲的措施
What drastic measures?
什麼意思?
Kill him.
幹掉他
Com'on.
走
Bhagat run! Quick!
Bhagat, 跑! 快!
You! Get going.
你來啊, 如果想死的話
On the day that followed
接下來的第二天
Azad, Bhagat Singh and others went missing
Azad, Bhagat Singh和其他人都不見了
This was the period when they coin the 2 words
正是這時他們創造了新詞
Inquilab Zindabad
Inquilab Zindabad (革命萬歲)
Two words that became the slogan for the Indian freedom movement.
這個詞成了印度自由運動的口號
Great idea!
好主意!
But Bhagat, escaping will be impossible.
但Bhagat, 這樣沒法逃脫
Our main mission is to get caught...
我們主要的任務是被抓..
...not escape.
而不是逃脫
What?
什麼?
If we get caught there will be a trial...
如果被抓將會有審判
...we'll get a chance to speak.
我們有機會發言
We'll be heard.
將會被聽到
But if they catch us, they'll hang us for certain.
可如果被抓, 一定會被絞死
I know.
我知道
But it takes a loud noise to open deaf ears.
要開啟聾子耳朵, 需要有力的呼喊
LONG LIVE THE REVOLUTION!
Inquilab Zindabad (革命萬歲)!
Smoke bombs
他們用了煙霧彈
intended to awaken England from her dreams
想讓英格蘭從美夢中甦醒
And they had more than achieve their task
而他們遠不止達成了目標
DOWN WITH IMPERIALISM!
帝國主義滅亡!
Feel the unrest
"感受這躁動.."
The embers, they are burning.
"餘燼在燃燒"
The tide, it's turning. You can feel the winds of change
"潮兒在漲動, 風兒在轉向"
Feel the unrest sweep through the land Feel the unrest
"感受這躁動.."
We are political prisoners...
我們是政治犯
...we should be allowed books... ...writing material...
應該可以給我們書本, 紙筆
...and at least one daily newspaper.
還有至少一份新聞日報
We will not eat till then. The hunger strike will continue.
拿不到就禁食, 會繼續抗議
The fast and torture went on for 114 days
禁食和拷打持續了114天
114 days
114天!
Never before in the history of any revolution that anyone last it so long
史上任何革命任何人也沒有持續過這麼久
in such a human conditions
在這樣的狀態下
We can crush these young boys
我們能摧毀他們的身體
but we cannot crush their soul
但摧不毀他們的靈魂
Our words won't falter now, We will speak our mind.
"言語不會畏懼, 我們道出心聲"
We won't back down now. Our dreams we won't leave behind.
"夢想不會放棄, 我們不會退縮"
We won't let the storm die. Injustice we will defy.
"風暴不會消亡, 我們反抗不公"
You can feel it possess you now. Feel it, your soul, claim.
"感受它佔據你, 感受你的靈魂"
Drink this spirit in one long swallow. Feel it course through your veins
"將這精神飲下, 感受它流淌全身"
Let the celebrations begin now. Feel your body sway.
"讓這狂歡開始, 感受身體搖擺"
In every breath feel more alive. To keep the storm at bay
"呼吸感受鮮活, 讓這風暴持續"
See the unrest in those eyes. See it all around.
"眼裏看到這躁動, 掃過整個大地"
See it in the air, my friend. And in those hearts, abound.
"還有心也在躁動, 感受這躁動"
Feel the unrest sweep through the land
"眼裏看到這躁動, 掃過整個大地"
See it in the air, my friend. And in those hearts, abound.
"還有心也在躁動, 感受這躁動"
The winds of change are blowing now The tide it is, a turning.
"風兒它已經轉向, 潮水也在漲動"
The moment of truth is upon us now It's time to do or die.
"為了真理而拚搏, 感受這躁動"
We are engulfed in the shadows But we will come out brighter.
"我們被那陰影吞沒, 出來時會更明亮"
Feel the unrest. Feel the unrest.
"感受這躁動.."
Pretty huh?
漂亮吧?
I like these ones
我喜歡它們
I think I'll buy them
可能會買下來
Pretty nice huh? Very pretty.
真的很漂亮
In breaking news today...
現在報道最新新聞..
...a MIG-21 fighter plane has just crashed...
一架MIG-21戰鬥機失事墜毀
...this is the second such crash in the past six months...
這是六個月來發生的第二起事故
The Defence Ministry has ordered an investigation into the crash.
國防部長已下令調查此事件
We have just received news that the pilot...
我們剛剛收到消息, 飛行員..
...Flight Lieutenant Ajay Rathod has died in the crash.
..Ajay Rathod上校在事故中遇難
Flight Lt Rathod apparently did not eject from the burning plane...
Rathod上校沒有從飛機上跳傘..
Instead he steered it away from Ambala city and crashed it in an open field.
而是將它開離Ambala, 墜毀在一片空地
Thus saving many lives
以此挽救生命
Viewers may recall...
觀眾也許還記得..
...that until now, 163 MiG-21 of IAF have crashed...
到目前為止, 印度空軍已有163架MIG-21失事..
...and 66 pilots have lost their lives.
66名飛行員喪生
This game of hide and seek has gone on too long, come home now, won't you.
"這'捉迷藏'玩得太久, 現在回家來吧"
I've searched high and low,
"我能去哪, 將你找尋"
these old eyes are weary so, come home now won't you.
"你的母親已疲倦"
Dusk is spreading like the ache in my heart,
"天色已晚, 我多麼擔心"
my vision blurs, come home now won't you.
"淚眼矇矓, 快回家來吧"
I'm in a place you wouldn't believe Ma.
"如何解釋我的所在, 媽"
Endless skies I can soar.
"無盡的天空任我翱翔"
Just like your fairy tales, it's filled with dreams.
"就像童話故事, 有著美麗, 純潔和夢幻"
A sea of hope with no shore.
"我的風箏就在這裏, 無憂無慮飛翔"
My soul flies here, like a kite without fear. No one to cut my strings, no more.
"希望沒人將線剪斷, 也不會被偷走"
Flt. Lt. Ajay Rathod stayed in the plane until the very end...
Ajay Rathod上校始終堅持到最後
...and steered the plane clear of Ambala city.
駕駛飛機飛離Ambala城
Thereby saving many lives.
從而挽救了許多生命
Unfortunately, the captain Ajay Rathod lost lives
然而Ajay Rathod上校卻犧牲了自己
In the last 10 years over 100 MIG-21 aircrafts of the IAF have crashed...
過去12年印度空軍有100多架MIG-21飛機墜毀
...in which over 30 pilots have lost their lives.
造成30多名飛行員喪生
Defence Minister, CAG report says old & defective Russian spare parts were procured by the govt.
國防部長請告訴我們, CAG(審計總署)報告稱 政府使用的是俄國破舊的零部件
Isn't this a case of high-level corruption?
這是否說明高層的腐敗?
Not at all. I've personally clarified the issue in parliament.
不, 當然不是. 我親自向議會澄清過
This is a downright lie.
這完全是污蔑
The youngsters of today are brash and irresponsible when it comes to flying planes.
現在的年輕人飛行時輕率而不負責
No! I don't agree...
不! 我不同意..
Flt. Lt. Ajay Rathod was an ace pilot...
Ajay Rathod是個飛行能手..
...who I trained...
是我調教的
He was a gold medallist. The youngest to clear night sorties.
他獲得過金牌獎章, 是最年輕的夜間飛行員
With over 1000 flying hours...
飛行超過1000小時
This can't be the record of an irresponsible pilot.
沒有哪個不負責的飛行員能做到這點
Defence Minister, how many more pilots will you send to their graves...
國防部長, 這體系的腐敗還會持續多久..
...before you stop the rot in the system?
你還會葬送多少飛行員的性命..?
If only I could show you this place, Ma.
"怎樣才能讓你看到這般景象"
Here waterfalls are made of rainbows.
"我在這裏所喝的水, 來自瀑布"
There are no roses just bouquets of dreams Ma. Their scent, no flower can hope for.
"我跳躍所觸及到的, 都是夢想"
Here sunlight and shadow walk hand in hand.
"想找陰涼卻發覺並不炎熱"
Everything seems bright and new.
"一切都是那樣地清新"
But what is heaven, and all its wonders,
"在這什麼都有, 媽可是"
when Ma, I don't have you.
"沒有你, 我覺得孤單"
From now on, the government will make sure that...
從現在起, 政府會敕令..
...only experienced pilots are given access to these machines...
只有經驗豐富的飛行員能駕駛這些飛機
...and not to rash pilots like Ajay Rathod.
而不是像Ajay Rathod這樣魯莽的飛行員
What the hell is he talking about!
他媽的在說些什麼!
I welcome any investigation. I have nothing to hide.
我歡迎任何調查, 我沒什麼好隱藏
This damn MIG investigation shouldn't take us down.
這該死的MiG調查不該影響我們
Relax Sir. Public memory is short. Besides, we'll handle things.
放心先生, 公眾的記憶短暫, 何況還有我們呢
Dead pilots, live very long in the news.
死去的飛行員, 媒體上會持續很久
But then, they join the forces to sacrifice their lives. Don't they?
然後人們就加入空軍去"犧牲", 不是嗎?
The situation is tense at the moment.
此刻形勢非常緊張
There is growing anger and discontent.
憤怒和不滿在增長
Directed largely towards the government. Especially the Defence Minister.
直接針對政府, 尤其是國防部長
We have with us Ajay Rathod's mother...
Ajay Rathod的母親就在這裏
The government can't wash its hands off the issue like this.
政府難逃其咎
They are answerable to the public.
他們應給公眾交待
If the MIG spare parts were of doubtful quality, why were they bought in the first place?
如果MiG的零件有質量隱患, 為什麼還要去買?
For what?
為了什麼?
Money?
為了錢嗎?
Money won't bring our children back.
但錢不能讓我兒子起死回生
The Defence Minister is morally responsible.
國防部長在道義上應受譴責
He has to resign.
他應該引退
It looks like the veil has been pulled off the defence scam.
看來國防部腐敗的面紗已被揭開
But how much will be revealed?
但是能暴露多少?
Mishra, what's happening?
Mishra, 是怎麼回事?
Ajay Rathod was not a novice...
Ajay Rathod不是個新手..
...he didn't let his plane crash into the town.
他沒有讓飛機墜落在城鎮
When it developed a snag he didn't try to save his life.
出現狀況時他沒有逃命
He steered it clear of Ambala ...saving thousands of civilians.
他駕離了Ambala, 救了上千的人民
Yet the Defence Minister calls him rash.
而國防部長卻稱他"輕率"
I'm not moving... this is for Ajay.
我不會走.. 這是為了Ajay
This could turn ugly, Aunty.
有可能變得不可收拾, 大嬸
Let it.
讓他們來吧
Our blood is ranging. It's flowing through the streets.
"為了改變這現狀"
But it won't go in vain
"血液在流淌"
Our eyes are blood shot for a purpose. A cause we will attain.
"映在我眼睛裏, 那血液在流淌"
It fell from our bodies, embraced the earth.
"從這身軀滴落, 附著這大地"
Went winding through streets. A river of courage ...it surged and swept.
"從大街小巷往外擴散, 流過.."
It flowed to make a new beginning
"為了創造新色彩, 血液在流淌"
From gaping wounds, and gashes large,
"隨著這敞開的傷口, 伴著這抽搐的疼痛"
it oozed, slowly and steadily.
"緩慢地, 緩慢地"
While the pointing fingers, got fists in reply,
"置疑的手指, 回應是拳頭"
yet, our blood was raging.
"與此同時"
It flowed not in vain but with a reason.
"血液在流淌"
A cause we will attain.
"為了改變這現狀, 血液在流淌"
Our eyes are blood shot for a reason. A cause we will attain.
"映在我眼睛裏, 血液在流淌"
Our blood is raging. It's flowing through the streets.
"從這身軀滴落, 附著這大地"
Went winding through streets. A river of courage ...it surged and swept.
"從大街小巷往外擴散, 流過.."
It flowed to make a new beginning Yet, our blood was raging.
"為了創造新色彩, 血液在流淌"
Yet, our blood was raging.
"血液在流淌"
Someone get a doctor! Quick! We'll take it from here.
快去叫醫生, 這裏交給我們
Please patient, we'll take care
請在這耐心等候, 我們會處理
They were beating up innocent people...
他們在毆打群眾..
Why didn't you stop them?
你為什麼不阻止?
You protested against the government, our own party...
你抗議政府, 我們自己的黨
That's unacceptable.
是不可接受的
The protest was not against the government...
抗議不是針對政府..
...it was for the truth.
而是為了真相
So many pilots have died...
死了這麼多飛行員
...young innocent boys who were fighting for our country... killed...
他們為國家戰鬥犧牲
...so that someone in the government could make money.
而政府裏有人拿這個來賺錢
And our party office doesn't do a thing about it.
我們的黨卻無動於衷
Come... Sit down.
來, 坐
Have some tea.
喝茶
Laxman, in politics there's no place for emotions.
Laxman, 政治是沒有感情的
We have big plans for you.
我們對你有很高的期望
Big plans.
很高期望
Only dogs salivate when you show them bone Mishraji.
Mishraji, 扔塊骨頭, 只有哈巴狗才搖頭晃尾
How's Aunty?
大媽還好嗎?
They're doing an MRI.
他們在做MRI掃瞄
She's slipped into a coma.
她陷入了昏迷
Severe skull damage, coupled with the shock of her son's death.
嚴重的腦損傷, 加上兒子死去的打擊
That's an ugly gash. You need attention.
有一道很深的傷口, 要特別注意
Aslam... How's he?
Aslam, Aslam怎麼樣?
What have you come for? Haven't you done enough damage?
你們來幹什麼? 做得還不夠?
Uncle, it isn't what you think.
伯伯, 不是你想的那樣
I'm not interested in what you think, In what you want to do...
我不感興趣你想什麼, 要說什麼..
I'm just going to say this once.
我只說這一次
Aslam doesn't know what's good for him.
Aslam不知道什麼才對他好
He's an emotional boy, always has been. He listens to his heart, not his head.
他容易衝動, 做事隨心不動腦
These are bad times, for people like us.
像我們這樣的人不好過
Don't take him down with you.
不要連累了他
He's inside. Go on...
進來吧, 他在裏面
All parts working?
各個部分還能運轉吧?
Don't make me laugh, idiot. It hurts
別惹我笑, 傻瓜. 很痛
How's Aunty?
大媽怎麼樣?
She's in a coma.
在昏迷
How can this be happening to us?
這種事怎麼會發生在我們身上?
Some dinner?
吃點東西嗎?
No, don't worry Aunty.
不伯母, 不麻煩了
We just came to see Aslam. We've got to get back to the hospital.
我們剛從醫院出來, 就來看看Aslam
Take care.
保重
Listen... I...
聽著, 我..
...I'm sorry.
我想跟你說
sorry
對不起
Please eat.
吃吧
Everything's falling apart...
什麼都一團糟
...and all I can do is stand and watch.
我只能站著看
People like us don't count out here.
我們這樣的人不起作用
This system is so messed up
體系這麼糟糕
a hundred more Ajay's can die
死100多個"Ajay"也無濟於事
and nothing will change.
什麼也不會變
Ajay did everything right, all his life...
Ajay什麼都做得很對, 他的一生
...he was a good pilot, a good friend, a good son...
他是個好飛行員, 好朋友, 好兒子
...he never harmed a soul.
從沒傷害過任何生命
...he didn't deserve this...
他不該是這個下場
...Sonia didn't deserve this...
Sonia也不該承受這痛苦
As I watch DJ sleep that night
那晚當我看著DJ睡覺
A funny thought caught me
我冒出了個奇怪的想法
Maybe DJ wasn't sleeping
也許DJ沒有睡去
Maybe none of them were
也許他們沒人是
Maybe they were all waking up
也許他們都在覺醒
Hey Karan... they've spoilt your jacket.
Karan, 他們在糟蹋你的夾克
Long live India!
印度萬歲!
The scoundrel got away with it again.
那個混蛋又逃脫了
There's nothing can we do...
我們什麼都做不了
...when the law of the land protects people like the Defence Minister.
當法律偏向這樣的人..
We have to take drastic measures.
我們就得採取嚴厲的行動
What do you mean?
什麼意思?
Do what?
要怎麼做?
Kill him.
殺掉他
What?
什麼?
Kill the Defence Minister!
殺掉國防部長
Are you crazy?
你們都瘋了?
We aren't killers Sonia.
我們不是殺人犯, Sonia
But they are.
但他們是
Have you lost it Karan!
你也瘋了, Karan?
It's not a blood lust...
這不是殺戮的慾望..
...it's a matter of justice.
而是為了正義
I'll get the gun.
我去搞槍
Don't fuel things, Pandey. We can't start killing people for any small reason.
不要火上澆油Pandey, 我們不能為了點小事殺人
You think Ajay's death is a small reason?
你覺得Ajay的死是小事?
Ajay's mother is a small reason?
Ajay的媽是小事?
You've got to understand Karan.
你要理解一下, Karan
Lala Lajpat Rai's death has to be avenged.
必須要為Lala Lajpat Rai的死報仇
Scott has to be killed.
Scott必須死
But...
可是..
I always thought we didn't believe in anything.
我一直以為我們什麼也不信
So did I
我也是
Until now.
直至今天
Have we all gone crazy?
我們都瘋了?
He takes a morning walk at 8 a.m. Everyday
他每天早上8點要散步
We'll kill him then.
我們在那時動手
Who's we, huh? Who's going to pull the trigger?
到時動手! 誰來動手? 我們誰來動手?
I'll do it!
我
Even though the morning security is relaxed there is still a danger of getting caught.
雖然早上警衛鬆懈, 但還是有被抓的危險
There is no looking back now!
現在沒機會回頭了
The Defence Minister was on his morning walk when two unidentified gunmen opened fire.
今天早上國防部長在散步時 兩個身份不明的持槍人向他開槍
He was hit by three bullets in his chest, and was declared dead as he reached the hospital.
他胸口中了三槍, 在去醫院途中死亡
No group has yet claimed responsibility for this incident.
沒有組織聲明對此負責
Government spokespersons believe that this is an attempt to destablise the government.
政府發言人認為這是試圖影響政府穩定
The country has lost a great leader because of the cowardly act of some terrorists.
因為某些膽小的恐怖行徑, 國家失去了一位偉大領袖
He was a true soldier, a true patriot.
他是個真正的愛國將士
His contribution to the country cannot be described in words.
他對國家的貢獻無法用言語表達
Sukhi!
Meanwhile our sources have discovered a telephonic conversation...
同時我們的線報捕獲了一次電話通話
...involving middle man Rajnath Singhania in an arms deal.
證明了中間商Rajnath Singhania參與了軍火交易
This conversation took place just a few days before the Defence Minister's assassination.
通話就發生在國防部長被刺的幾天前
The Russians want us to reduce our commission.
'俄國人想降低我們的佣金'
Didn't you tell them, its not a defence deal, but our deal.
'你沒跟他們說, 這不是國防部的交易, 而是我們的交易'
That's why I told them. - "Take it or leave it"
'所以我跟他們說, 他們自己看著辦'
Let's go.
我們走
Paaji, where's DJ?
Paaji, DJ在哪?
They were just here.
他們剛才還在這
He hasn't come home all night.
他整晚都沒回來
Is everything alright?
沒什麼事吧?
He said he'd be spending the night at DJ's.
他說要在DJ那過夜
Have you seen DJ?
看見DJ嗎?
Is everything alright?
沒事吧?
I can't find him
我找不到他
I can't find anyone, Sonia, or Aslam I don't know where they are
我誰都找不到, Sonia, Aslam, 不知道他們在哪
Come with me...
過來..
Sit
坐
Don't worry... nothing will happen to those boys...
別擔心.. 他們會沒事的
Daljeet has always been a brat...
Daljeet就是這麼淘氣
...he used to disappear on his bike for days...
他曾經開著摩托車, 消失好幾天
I'm scared...
我害怕..
Don't be afraid...
不要怕
God will take care of everything...
老天會保佑他們的
God watches over the people we love.
我們愛的人, 老天會照顧他們
Defence Minister... the martyr...
國防部長, 烈士..
...one of India's favourite sons... Scoundrel!
印度最可愛的兒子..
They're honouring him with the National Medal of Honour.
他們要給他國家榮譽勳章
All our efforts, wasted.
我們的努力, 白費了
People need to know the truth.
人們需要知道真相
...and who's going to tell them the truth?
是嗎? 誰去說出真相?
We have to surrender ourselves.
我們! 我們要去自首
What?
什麼?
Terriffic! You want us to walk right in and give ourselves up!
警官, 抓我吧, 抓我吧, 我們要自首
And who should we surrenderto?
我們跟誰自首?
The police are mere puppets.
警察, 不過是受制於人
Should we just sit back?
那怎麼辦? 就這樣坐著? 什麼也不做?
No! Let's kill them all!
不! 把他們都殺了!
Right Pandey?
是嗎 Pandey?
Someone make him shut up!
誰讓他閉嘴!
You always knew that your father was in it.
你早就知道你爸有份
You knew everything.
你什麼都知道
No Sukhi...
我不知道, Sukhi..
You're lying!
你在說謊!
You always wanted to take revenge on your father.
你一直想向你爸報仇
Sukhi, shut up!
Sukhi, 不要說了!
Who am I to say anything?
我是誰, 憑什麼說他?
DJ he's used you...
DJ他是在利用你
...he's used all of us...
利用了我們所有人
Mark my words, his father will bail him out.
記住我說的話, 他爸會保他出去
But we'll get caught. And I don't want to die DJ...
我們會被抓, 而我還不想死..
I don't want to die.
我不想死..
We did all this for Ajay.
我們這麼做都是為了Ajay
What will happen now DJ?
現在怎麼辦DJ?
You've decided?
你想好了?
I need to know the truth...
我得知道真相..
don't worry.
別擔心
I'm not worried. Just don't be late.
我不擔心, 只是別太晚
Nothing will happen to you Karan.
你不會有事的Karan
That's a promise.
我向你保證不會有事的
Just give me the names of the others.
只要把其它人的名字告訴我
I'll get you the best lawyers, pull all the strings possible.
我會請最好的律師, 想盡一切辦法
You were forced into it, do you understand? You were forced.
你是被逼的, 知道嗎? 是被逼的
And then you are out of this country
然後你就離開這個國家
Do you get me?
說話啊? 聽到沒有?
Say something, damn it
說話啊, 媽的!
Your father's reputation, his life's work is at stake.
你父親的名譽, 一生的事業都危在旦夕
Why did you do it?
你為什麼這麼做? 為什麼?
Why did you do it, Dad?
你為什麼這麼做?
What did I do?
我? 我做什麼了?
Ajay always said, "I'll give my life for this country."
Ajay總是說, "我會為國家獻身"
"...I'm not afraid of death."
"我不害怕死亡, 什麼也不怕"
and all you can think of is sending me out of the country...
而你想的, 卻是逃亡出國
Ajay was burnt alive...
Ajay他被活活燒死
You killed him!
是你殺了他
You made a joke of his death...
你把他的生命當兒戲
I know you're very disturbed...
我知道你很難受
Relax! Let me handle things.
但你什麼也不要想, 這事我來處理
I'll find a way out.
我會想到辦法的
Really Dad? Is there a way out?
只有一個辦法, 爸
Of course.
當然
You are going out of this country tonight
你今晚就出國
You don't have to do this...
Sukhi, 你沒必要這麼做
Sukhi, this might end badly.
Sukhi, 結局可能很糟糕
Without you guys it will end for me anyway...
反正沒有你們, 我也一樣糟糕
Idiot.
傻小子
Ajay's death, won't go in vain, Ma. I promise you.
媽, 我答應你, Ajay不會白死的
What is it about these boys that makes them have no fear?
是什麼讓這些人毫無畏懼?
I think sometimes a person can be pushed so far
我想有時一個人能走這麼遠
that will to place beyond the fear
到達超越恐懼的地步
A place where find strange peace
在那裏找到奇怪的安寧
where you'll free yourself to do the right thing
可以自由地做正確的事
Because sometimes, that's the hardest thing to do
因為有時, 這也是最難做到的事
Then I prayed for it
然後我祈禱
I prayed for forgiveness
祈求原諒
This is Rahul, and you've tuned in to your favourite radio show...
歡迎回來, 這裏是... 你最喜歡的電台, 我是Rahul..
Hey Karan! What're you doing here?
Karan, 真叫人驚喜! 你們怎麼來了?
We need a favour.
我們要你幫個忙
Sure!
當然
I need you to put us on air.
我們需要上電台
Put you on air?
上廣播電台?
Yeah, now!
是, 直播!
That's impossible man... I'll lose my job.
'是, 現在, 直播'那是不可能的, 我會丟工作的
...as it is, they don't pay me.
而且其實他們不付我錢
It's payback time.
那麼現在該付你了
Hey! Whateveryou say DJ! It's your station.
好吧好吧, 你怎麼說都好DJ! 電台都是你的
Gun... He's got a gun!
槍! 他有槍!
Karan you go in. I'll handle it.
Karan你進去, 我來處理
Keep the show on. Don't mess with us.
繼續播音, 別耍花招, 知道嗎?
Come on... leave.
來, 走吧
Paaji is anyone inside?
Paaji, 裏面還有人嗎?
Uncleji run. Don't stop.
Uncleji, 走, 別停下
Gun... Security he's got a gun!
槍.. 保安他有槍!
Don't be a wise guy.
別自作聰明
Everybody leave! Out! Move!
每個人都出去!
Don't panic we won't harm anyone.
別慌張, 我們不會傷害任何人
Move! Move! Move!
走走!
Hurry up, quick!
快點, 快!
The time is 6:05 a.m. And you're listening to "The night is still young".
現在是早上6點05分. 你現正收聽的是"夜色仍淡"
Today I've got a surprise guest for you.
今天我們請到了一個特殊嘉賓
An old friend of mine Karan Singhania, who just dropped in to say something to all of you...
我的一個老朋友Karan Singhania, 有話與大家分享
My name is Karan Singhania... My friends and I... we killed the Defence Minister...
我叫Karan Singhania, 我和我的朋友殺死了國防部長
I repeat we killed the Defence Minister...
我再說一遍, 我和我的朋友殺死了國防部長
Ravi take me to the radio station quickly. Hurry up!
Ravi馬上帶我去廣播站, 趕快!
We are not terrorists. We aren't backed by any foreign organisation.
我們不是恐怖分子, 背後也沒有什麼國外組織
We don't even belong to any political group...
我們不屬於任何下政治組織
We're just five students from Delhi University.
我們只是德裏大學的5個學生
We killed the Defense Minister because...
我們殺害了國防部長..
...he murdered ourfriend Flight Lieutenant Ajay Rathod and many other Air Force pilots...
因為他害死了我們的朋友Ajay Rathod上校 和其它很多的空軍飛行員
We killed him because after he murdered Ajay, he murdered his name...
我們殺了他因為他不僅害死了Ajay 還詆毀了他的名譽
Ajay's mother, right now, is fighting for her life...
Ajay的母親現在還在死亡線上掙扎
A Defence Minister is supposed to safegaurd a nation. Not sell it.
國防部長應該保衛國家, 而不是出賣國家
Men like the Defence Minister aren't just above the law... they control it.
像他那樣的人不僅凌駕法律之上, 而且一手操控
We killed him because someone had to say, "Enough!".
我們殺了他因為必須有人站出來抗議
We might be wrong...
我們也許錯了
...because its a sin to kill someone.
因為殺人是罪過
But we couldn't tolerate it anymore.
但我們再也忍受不了了
Today we are here to confess to our sin.
今天我們在此坦白我們的罪過
Today we are here to tell everybody that something has to be done
今天我們在此告訴每個人, 應該行動了
It's got to be done.
必須行動了
We've just received news that Defence Minister's assassins are hiding in All India Radio building.
我們剛得到消息國防部長的行刺者躲在"All India"廣播大樓
Karan Singhania and his friends are still with us. Listeners can call in on 3291777.
Karan Singhania與他的朋友仍然在線 聽眾可以撥打3291777
Until then, here is "Roobaroo"
先來段音樂
It's done.
說完了
Hey, dude!
"嘿夥計"
I just realized.
"現在明白了"
There's a fire burning within me.
"有一團火, 在胸中燃燒"
It's a new dawn,
"新的黎明"
I can feel its light
"感受到光線"
Burn so bright, I could, scorch the sun
"這麼明亮, 能把太陽烘烤"
'Cause I'm face to face with the light
"我與這光, 面對面"
The dream I once lost, I've found.
"這些夢想, 曾經失去"
It's blooming,
"重新找回, 它在盛放"
it's melting,
"猶如鋼鐵, 已經融化"
notes re-arranging,
"再次鍛造, 得到昇華"
into a whole new melody.
"它變成了, 星星的模樣"
Will they give us good food in jail?
監獄有好吃的嗎?
Food? Next he'll want beer.
好吃的? 接下來就想要啤酒了
You guys have become famous. Calls are pouring in from all overthe country.
你們出名了, 全國各地的電話都打來了
Come on! They want to talk to you...
來啊, 他們想跟你說話
Police!
警察!
This is unreal man. Where did they come from?
這不是真的. 他們從哪來的?
This will ruin my career...
我的事業要毀了
Shut up!
閉嘴
Karan you get on air... We don't have much time...
Karan你去播音.. 我們沒多少時間了
Take care.
保重
The Delhi police have reached the spot and are rescuing civilians trapped in the building.
德裏警方到達現場, 正對大樓被困的人進行救援
...reporting from Mumbai's Churchgate area...
..從孟買教堂門地區報道..
...reporting from Cotton College, Guwahati.
..從古瓦哈蒂的科頓大學報道..
...reporting from S. P. College, Srinagar...
..從斯利那加的S.P.大學報道..
...reporting from Lucknow University...
..從勒克瑙大學報道..
Hi, my name is Prakash. And I want to congratulate you.
我叫Prakash, 我想向你道賀
You did the right thing by killing him. All our ministers should be lined up and shot.
你們殺了他做得對, 所有部長都該排起隊來受死
Prakash, who all will you shoot?
Prakash, 你會殺掉哪一些部長?
These corrupt ministers are a reflection of our society. We've chosen them.
這些腐敗的部長是根據社會反映而選擇的
We need to change ourselves to bring about a change.
我們要改變自己從而帶來改變
Hello! This is Principal Sharma from Indore...
我是Indore的Sharma校長..
You have set a terrible example by taking the law into your own hands.
你們當自己是法律樹立了很壞的榜樣
You're right sir. We're sorry.
說得對, 我們很抱歉
But give me the name of one politician who has gone to jail for his crimes.
但是你說說有哪個政治家因為罪行入了監獄
Who else is on your hit-list? I
你的暗殺名單上還有誰?
We have no hit-list.
我們沒有暗殺名單
How do you feel after killing the Defence Minister?
殺掉了國防部長你有什麼感覺?
We did not kill him out of any blood lust...
我們殺了他不是出於殺戮欲
If you get caught you'll be hanged. Aren't you afraid?
如果被抓你們會被絞死, 你們不怕?
No.
不怕
The college students who have claimed responsibility...
聲稱對此負責的大學生
...are still inside.
還在裏面
Karan, while we applaud your courage, do you think you'll escape?
Karan, 當我們為你們的勇氣鼓掌時, 你們想過逃跑沒?
If we wanted to escape, we wouldn't have been here in the first place.
要是想逃就不來這了
Do not spare anyone.
一個也不要放過
I don't want any survivor
我不想有任何倖存者
Shit! They're shooting at us DJ! They're shooting at us!
我的老天, 他們在向我們開槍, DJ! ..
Shut up for a second!
冷靜一下!
They're mistaking us for terrorists. They think we're armed.
他們誤以為我們是恐怖分子, 以為我們有武器
Wait a minute! I'll try to handle it.
等一會, 我來處理
No Sukhi! What did you do!
看看你都做了什麼
Shit DJ! Just when I was getting good with the girls...
傻DJ, 我剛要和女孩子好上..
My name is Indra. What's the difference between you and a terrorist?
我叫Indra, 你們和恐怖分子有什麼區別呢?
There's a big difference. Terrorists kill innocent people. We didn't...
有很大區別, 恐怖分子殺害無辜的人, 我們沒有..
Aslam, close the door. Quick!
快關上門
We are not terrorists. Why don't they...
我們不是恐怖分子, 他們怎麼..
It's not a lust for blood... it's a matter of justice!
這不是殺戮欲, 而是為了正義
Why are bullets being used when its clear that these are college students?
已經很清楚是群大學生, 為什麼還要使用子彈?
No matter what you do, this country will never change. It has no future.
不管你們怎麼做, 國家都不會變化 這裏是印度, 它沒有未來
No country is perfect. You've got to make it perfect.
沒有國家是完美的, 只能讓它變得更好
Join the police, military, IAS...
加入警局, 軍隊, IAS(印度科學院)
Become a part of the political system...
成為政治體系的一分子
This country will change... We will change it!
國家會變的, 我們會改變她的
If you believed the Defence Minister deserved to be punished then...
如果你們相信國防部長應該受到懲罰..
...what about the allegations against your father? Why such double standards?
那你的父親呢? 怎麼說一套做一套?
We'll find a way to fix this.
我們會想出辦法來的
There's just one way to fix this Dad.
只有一個辦法, 爸
I'm sorry Dad...
對不起, 爸爸
My name is Daljeet Singh.
我叫Daljeet Singh.
There are only two ways to live your life.
生命有兩種活法
Tolerate things the way they are...
忍受現有的方式
...Ortake responsibility to change them.
或者, 負起責任來改變
Karan Singhania killed his father before coming here.
Karan Singhania來這之前已經殺了自己的父親
Shit DJ! You're bleeding badly!
你流了很多血!
Relax! It got tired of flowing in my veins. It just wanted to be free.
放鬆, 它在我血管裏待膩了, 它也想要自由
Aslam.. Laxman.. Sukhi?
Aslam... Laxman... Sukhi?
All gone.
都死了
...Karan, I think I'm in love...
Karan, 我想我戀愛了
...I nevertold you dude...
我從沒告訴過你們
...I can't stop thinking about her...
我止不住對她的思念
I know... she's something else.
我知道, 她與眾不同
You two'll make a great couple.
你們兩個會成為很配的一對
There's just one problem though.
只有一個問題
I don't know Whether the kids will be black or white.
我不知道孩子會是黑還是白
Let me go! They're just boys, damn it!
放開我! 他們不過是少年!
I always believe there were two kinds of men in this world
我一直認為世界上有兩種人
One who go to that death screaming
面對死亡哭喊的人
And men who go to that death in silence
面對死亡安靜的人
And then I met the third kind
然後我遇到了第三種
Sending commandos is the death of democracy
派出突擊隊是民主制度的死亡
Today is a sad day in the history of Indian politics
今天是印度政治歷史上悲傷的一天
We'll turn this spark into a raging fire.
我們會把這火花演變成熊熊火焰
This will swell like a wave and will bring an end to corruption.
這會像洶涌的波濤終結這腐敗
The truth has to come out some way and if it has to come out this way then we are all for it
真相必須得到揭露, 如果 非要以這樣的方式, 那我們都會贊同
If we want to shake the entire population out of their slumber then we need an explosion like this.
要想撼醒全國的人民, 我們就需要這樣的"炸彈"
We are going to sit and just talk about the thing So we got to do some steps
我們不能總坐著討論這些, 必須付諸行動
And they have done it, they have taken a right step..
而他們做到了, 他們做了正確的舉動
When we grow out of this, well be a nation which is beautiful and free of corruption.
等我們從這裏成長起來, 國家會變得美好沒有腐敗
in minds and hearts, that's not gonna fix up very soon And we'll see that
深深打動了我們的心, 不會很快忘記 我們會讓夢想成為現實
We will do it
我們會行動起來
Lord, accept the sacrifices of these children.
神啊, 請接受這些孩子的犧牲
I come here with Sonia a lot
我經常與Sonia來這
Just like old times
就像以前一樣
And sometimes I hear voices carried by the evening breeze
有時我聽見傍晚的微風帶來聲音
Not words, just sounds
不是說話聲, 只是聲音
Sounds of laughter
歡笑聲
Come Bhagat...
過來, Bhagat..
Dad, what are you doing?
爸爸, 你在幹什麼?
I'm sowing mango seeds. If I plant one, a thousand will grow.
我在播芒果種, 撒下一顆, 長出成片
MiG fighter planes have served our country since 1964 and have been instrumental in winning us wars
印度從1964年即開始使用MiG戰鬥機 在戰役中起了相當作用
However over the 15 years, 206 MiG planes have crashed and 78 pilots have lost their lives
然而15年來, 有206架MiG飛機墜毀, 78名飛行員喪生
In their memory and in honour of our Air Borne Warriors who have laid down their lives for our country
為紀念這些空中勇士, 紀念他們為祖國獻出了生命